🗈 tbd

in fluz

fluz

🔰 fluz

Fernando Luz

About me

15+ years of developing and working in projects led me to have hands-on experience solving complex problems in software development using several languages and frameworks across a wide range of companies, including startups, oil and gas industries, educational institutions, and research labs. Driven self-starter and fast learner, always supporting my development teams with top-notch coding skills. I enjoy the challenge to maintain team cooperation to achieve objectives/deliveries in the process development. I strongly believe that sharing knowledge is a key point in a dev team, and I do my best to write clear and good code and implement best practices.

Experience

2022 -

Present Management of the HLS — Healthcare & Life Science stream and Support stream at Industries BU. (manager of 10+ Individual Contributors from entry levels to leads) The HLS stream is responsible for Healthcare Experience Cloud development, integrating healthcare call centers with unified patient information. The Support stream teams are composed of two squads. The Cross Industries team implements tools and integrations to be used in other projects in our BU. The QA team provides a framework and procedure to validate the quality of our products.

2021 - 2022

Integrate a new team from the ground to create a new solution for banking financial services. The tech stack in this project uses Kotlin (BE), SpringBoot, React (FE), Redis, PostGres SQL, MongoDB, RabbitMQ.

2018 - 2021

Responsible to start the ASML project, where I contributed in Variant Pattern implementation at the robot component to be used in next lithography machine generation (EXE-5000), and currently I'm leading the Portugal team to expand unit tests quality using a framework based on gtest. I was one of the founders in the Meetup internal group in Altran PT.

2016 - 2018

Managed the team responsible to implement new features in the TMS (Technomar Maritime Simulator). TMS is a vessel maneuver simulator used in training activities. Launched the certification planning for TMS simulator by DNV GL agency, and the collaborated in the the core of hydrodynamic numerical model applied in a "full bridge" simulator. Cultivated good practices in software development process, such as Scrum/Kanban board, TDD, Git adoption and mentored meeting sessions to promote the homogenization of the knowledge of the team.

2008 - 2016

My role in the TPN laboratory was to develop a set of applications with High-Performance Computing. The languages I use was C++/C, Python, MPI/sockets and bash in Linux and Windows environment. Other duties includes testing and validation of numerical simulations, optimization, implementation of parallel improvements and integration with other projects. I also worked in others several projects, including the first version of vessel maneuver simulator called SMH. This project was select as finalist of ANP (National **Petroleum Agency)** Prize Award for Technological Innovation in 2016.

2011 - 2016

Teaching-related responsibilities such as giving lectures, tutoring, manage homeworks, laboratory activities, exams preparation and grading.

Education

2015 . 2010 .

2006 .

Other courses

Languages